The answer is 2499.
It's just 12,495 divided by 5,
and the remainder becomes 9996.
When you work this out for all iterations of the puzzle,
you'll find that in the morning when they wake up
there's 5116 coconuts left, just about a third.
The monkey gets 1, and each of the people take with them yet another 1023 coconuts.
Now, why is this an interesting quiz?
Because there's another solution.
That one is really hard, but it's also very elegant; very, very elegant.
Let me build up the solution by finding a really simple number that
satisfies the variance of giving 1 to the monkey, removing a 5th.
Now, such a number is impossible to find in the set of positive numbers,
but here is one that works: -4.
If we subtract 1, you get -5.
If you now take a 5th away, which happens to be -1,
then the result is -4 again.
So you can keep doing this, and you'll always arrive at -4.
So -4 is a valid solution to the puzzle except it is negative,
and it's hard to think of negative numbers of coconuts.