So the answer is tricky.
I'm going to use a variable n that I increment by 1 in this while loop over here.
And I'm using a flag called "found" that I initialized with False.
And so as long as I don't find a valid number, I just go up by 1 over here.
And when I find it, I terminate the while loop, and I print the result.
And this is the tricky part over here.
So I'm testing the function f6 for is_int,
but when I pass my argument, I make sure it's actually a floating value argument,
not an integer; otherwise the procedure doesn't work.
This is a tricky part about Python and type treatment in Python.
This makes sure I'm using a floating point number,
and the loop over here when I hit run gives me 15,621.
Did you get it?