Suppose we multiply two Gaussians as in Bayes rule,
a prior and a measurement probability.
And the prior has a mean of μ and a variance of σ².
The measurement has a mean of ν and a covariance of r².
Then the new mean, μ', is the weighted sum of the old means
where μ is weighted by r², ν is weighted by σ²
normalized by the sum of those weighting factors.
And the new variance term, I'm going to write σ²' here
for the new one after the update, is given by this equation over here.
So let's put this into action.
We have a weighted mean over here.
Clearly, the prior Guassian has a much higher uncertainty.
Therefore σ² is larger.
And that means that ν is weighted much, much larger than the μ.
So the mean will be closer to the ν than the μ,
which means that it'll be somewhere over here.
Interestingly enough, the variance term is unaffected by the actual means.
It just uses the previous variances and comes up with a new one that's even peakier.
So the result might look like this.
So this is the common situation for the measurement update step
where this is the prior, this is the measurement probability, and this is the posterior.
So let's practice these equations with a simple quiz.
So here are our equations again.
And suppose I use the following Gaussians:
These are Gaussians with equal variance but different means that might look as follows.
Compute for me the new mean after the update and the new σ².