And the answer is, 0.0079.
In other words, there is only a 0.79 percent chance,
0.79 out of 100,
that despite the positive test result, that you have cancer.
And we're going to apply the exact same mechanics as we did before.
The result of Bayes Rule, non-normalized, of c given pos,
is simply the product of my prior probability, 0.01,
times 0.8, which is the probability of
a positive result in the cancer state.
And that ends up to be 0.0008.
The non-normalized probability for the opposite event,
the non-cancerous event, given a positive test, is 0.999
times 0.1, and that is obviously 0.0999.
Our normalizer, and so the sum of both of those,
which is 0.1007, just add these 2 values up over here.
So dividing 0.0008, the non-normalized probability,
by 0.1007, gives us 0.079.
We just applied Bayes Rule to compute a really involved probability
of having cancer after seeing a test result.