So here's our first programming exercise.
I'd like you to make a robot that starts at coordinates 30 and 50,
and it heads north, which means its heading direction is pi/2.
It then turns clockwise by pi/2, which means you subtract pi/2 from the heading direction,
and it moves 50 meters.
It then senses, and I want you to print out the sensor measurements.
It then turns clockwise by pi/2, again, and moves 10 meters this time,
and I just want you to print out the sensor measurements after this entire procedure.
So, there are 2 print statements for the sensor over here
and the sensor measurements over here.
So, here's the output I would like your program to generate.
After the first motion, the first measurements will be 39 + something,
46, 39, and 46,
and then after the second motion I expect to see 32, 53, 47, 40.
Of course, there's lots of decimal-point numbers over here,
but these are the numbers I would expect you to output.
So, have fun coding it.