So welcome to our very first homework assignment.
This is number 1.
Just to recap, in the class we learned about localization.
We learned about about histogram filters.
And we programmed some in Python.
So the homework assignment will cover this plus some very basic probability.
In the first question, I'm going to ask you some very basic probability questions.
We have a random variable X and probability 0.2.
What's the probability of the complement?
We have 2 random variables, X and Y, whose probability individually is 0.2.
And X and Y are independent.
What's the probability of the joint X, Y?
And we have the variable P(X) with probability 0.2,
and we have 2 conditionals, P(Y|X) and P(Y|¬X), both 0.6.
What's the probability of Y?
Here you have to apply total probability.